

Alexey Saechnikov

iOS Developer

Passionate iOS developer who gets great satisfaction from taking an app through the production cycle to it's launch. Has experience of leading teams of 3-5 people and is particularly interested in building or improving a stable architecture for applications to improve their scalability. Fast and enthusiastic learner with interesting and diverse experiences.

MINSK, BELARUS

iOS, OS X, Watch OS, tvOS, CI and CD.

KEY SKILLS

TECHNICAL SKILLS YEARS OF EXPERIENCE PROFICIENCY

Swift 4 (since 2016) *****

Objective C 8 (since 2012) *****

WORK EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer 2021 - current

Excelsior Solutions

https://www.excelsior-solutions.de/

working on current and new applications

Lead iOS Developer (remote)

2017 - 2020

Tapp Solutions

https://www.tappsolutions.com/

- Planning and implementing project architecture
- Developing frameworks to reuse in all complany applications
- Support existing applications

Freelance Developer

2015 - 2020

Upwork, personal connections

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~0164318e9deae07ccb

- Searching for new clients
- Preparing specifications

 Gathering and 	cation architecture managing developers team d integrating applications and systems	
iOS Developer		2012 - 2015
VironIT http://vironit.com		
Deploying appManaging dev	elopers team ew candidates for developer job	
SharePoint Administrator		2011 - 2012
BSUIR http://bsuir.by		
 SharePoint ins 		
EDUCATION & CE	<u>ERTIFICATES</u>	
Bachelor's degree BELARUSIAN STATE UNIVERSITY OF INFORMATICS AND RADIOELECTRONICS Electronic Computing		2007 - 2012
High School Education COLLEGE-PREPARATORY SCHOOL Mathematics, Physics		2005 - 2007
Primary Education PREPARATORY SCHOOL		1996 - 2005
LANGUAGES		
English	Advanced	
Russian	Native or bilingual	